# **MOHAMED YEHIA**

Cleveland, Ohio | (419) 779-3203 | Massem1983@yahoo.com

Linkedin || GitHub

# **Summary**

I'm a positive, team-oriented professional with a unique skill set, combining problem solving skills developed as retail general Manager with 10+ years in business management. I have always had a knack for problem solving and I'm always carious and love to learn, and becoming a developer has always interested me. I'm looking to use my problem solving skills and business management experience as a foundation for a junior developer role that allows me to collaborate with a team and continue to grow my coding skills.

#### **Technical Skills**

• Object Oriented Programming: Java

• Web App Development: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Servlets, JSP, Spring Web MVC, Tomcat

• Database Programing: JDBC, table design and creation, SQL queries, PostgreSQL

• **Development techniques:** Agile, Junit Testing, Git, Eclipse, Visual Studio

## Education

#### Tech Elevator – Cleveland, OH

May 2018 - August 2018

Attended a 14-week Java coding bootcamp learned how to develop dynamic web-based software systems using the Java programming language.

# Alexandria University - Egypt

August 2001 – June 2002

Faculty Of Law – Credits

# **Technical Experience**

- Vending Machine Application: Developed in Java using OOP fundamentals using file Input/Output.
- National Park Reservation: Developed a command line interface Reservation page for National Park tours in Java and PostgreSQL.
- National Park Information and Weather Website: Database driven website developed using Spring MVC, JSP, Tomcat, and SQL.
- Walk CLE Website: Database driven website developed using Spring MVC, JSP, Tomcat, and SQL.

# **Professional Experience**

# Glitter, Toledo, OH

## **General Manager**

September 2011 – April 2018

- Trained store staff by reviewing and revising orientation to products and sales training materials.
- Optimized profits by controlling merchandise and labor costs on a daily basis.
- Scheduled and directed staff in daily work assignments to maximize productivity.
- Conducted daily pre-shift and weekly departmental meetings to ensure organizational efficiency.

## Signature, Westland, MI

January 2006 - August 2011

#### **Assistant Manager**

- Assisted store manager in implementing strategies to increase store sales.
- Coordinated daily customer service operations including sales processes, orders, and payments.
- Optimized profits by controlling inventory and ensuring product quality and availability.

# Alexandria University, Alexandria – Egypt

2002 - 2005

## **Student Affairs Specialist**

- Coordinated and enforced dean of students policies and procedures, and ensured compatibility with local
  operating policies university-wide.
- Designed, developed, coordinated, and presented a wide range of workshops and conferences.